<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2022 Xargon <xargonwan@gmail.com> and the RetroDECK Team-->
<component type="desktop-application">
   <id>net.retrodeck.retrodeck</id>
   <launchable type="desktop-id">net.retrodeck.retrodeck.desktop</launchable>
   <name>RetroDECK</name>
   <summary>RetroDECK brings an environment to catalog and play your retro games directly on your Steam Deck.</summary>
   <developer_name>RetroDECK Team</developer_name>
   <url type="homepage">https://retrodeck.net</url>
   <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/issues</url>
   <url type="help">http://discord.gg/Dz3szYsP8g</url>
   <url type="faq">https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/wiki/FAQs---Frequently-asked-questions</url>
   <url type="donation">https://www.patreon.com/RetroDECK</url>
   <content_rating type="oars-1.0" />
   <screenshots>
      <screenshot type="default">
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/logo.png?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen01.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen02.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen03.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen04.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen05.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
      <screenshot>
         <image>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/blob/main/res/screenshots/screen06.jpeg?raw=true</image>
      </screenshot>
   </screenshots>
   <description>
      <p>What is Retrodeck?</p>
      <p>RetroDECK is an emulation and retro gaming solution to catalog and play your game collection directly from Linux in one unified application.
  It's inspired by other embedded emulation systems like AmberELEC, EmuELEC, CoreELEC, Lakka, and Batocera.
  RetroDECK is powered by EmulationStation Desktop Edition, that uses RetroArch and other standalone emulators to allow you to import and play your favorite games in a tidy environment.
  No other software is needed as everything it's already included in one package!</p>
      <p>BETA NOTICE: RetroDECK is still in Beta and the team is actively developing and adding more features.
         The primary focus during the beta period is on SteamOS and the Steam Deck but we hope to expand to more devices and general Linux desktop in the future</p>
      <p>NOTE: It can be run on Linux desktop right now but there will be some manual configurations needed for input, storage location and other tiny hickups.</p>
      <p>
         INSTALLATION INSTRUCTIONS FOR THE STEAM DECK:
         <ul>
            <li>1. Start RetroDECK from the Desktop mode (only needed for the initial first time configuration)</li>
            <li>2. Add RetroDECK to your Steam Library by pressing "Add a non-steam game to my library"</li>
            <li>3. Download the offical RetroDECK controller profile from Steam</li>
            <li>4. [OPTIONAL] Download Steam Grids graphics for RetroDECK with BoilR</li>
         </ul>
      </p>
      <p>For more detailed information check our wiki: 
      https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/wiki</p>
      <p>If you want to sponsor the project: 
      https://www.patreon.com/RetroDECK</p>
      <p>If you want to join the RetroDECK community check our:</p>
      <p>Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/RetroDECK/</p>
      <p>Discord: https://discord.gg/Dz3szYsP8g 
         (If you want to help out with the project join the "i-want-to-help" channel)</p>
   </description>
   <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
   <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
   <releases>
      <release version="0.8.0b" date="2023-09-28">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.8.0b</url>
         <description>
            <p>News:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Welcome to cooker 0.8.0b!</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.7.2b" date="2023-09-27">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.7.2b</url>
         <description>
            <p>Updates:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>All Emulators, ES-DE and the included theme have been updated.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Bugfixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Added helper .txt files to the mod and texture pack folders.</li>
               <li>The builtin changelog is now scrollable.</li>
               <li>The loading bar color is after much debate once again red.</li>
               <li>Gameboy Advanced and Game Gear integer scaling changes based on feedback.</li>
               <li>Optimized and retooled the patching process for ES-DE.</li>
               <li>Various fixes and optimizations to the RetroDECK build process.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Known issues:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>PPSSPP now have Retroachievements, but it is right now not configurable in the configurator (as it works a bit different the other emulators), we hope to have a solution for it at a later date. You can still login / logout / enable hardcore mode normally from the PPSSPP interface.</li>
               <li>Quitting the RetroArch GB core with the radial function makes the core swap the palette.</li>
               <li>Borders sometimes are disappearing, a possible workaround is to reset RetroArch from the configurator.</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.7.1b" date="2023-08-16">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.7.1b</url>
         <description>
            <p>Information:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Steam Deck users update RetroDECK from <i>Discover</i> in Desktop Mode.</li>
                <li>Don't forget to reapply the latest controller layout: Go into the <i>Templates</i> tab and reapply the new profile ending with 0.7.1b (there is no need to reinstall the entire layout from the Configurator).</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Bug fixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Fixed an issue to make sure the RD controller layout file at update with each RD update.</li>
                <li>Fixed an issue with PPSSPP that made <i>L</i> and <i>R</i> incorrectly bound.</li>
                <li>Fixed an issue in the Configurator that prevented the Yuzu preset for swapping A/B X/Y from working.</li>
                <li>Fixed a notification issue on the latest SteamOS Beta releases.</li>
                <li>Fixed an rsync permissions issue in the RetroDECK Framework.</li>
                <li>Updated Yuzu presets to handle new config syntax in the RetroDECK Framework.</li>
                <li>Changed auto-update to notification only, until permissions error can be worked out.</li>
                <li>Added some new pixelart icons by ItzSelenux (pixelitos-icon-theme)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Updates:</p>
            <p>All Emulators and ES-DE have been updated</p>
            <p>Steam Deck - Global Controller Layout:</p>
            <p>We have done some changes based on community feedback</p>
            <ul>
                <li><i>Select</i> is now a hotkey trigger while pressing it down, <i>L4</i> and <i>R4</i> are still triggers as well.</li>
                <li>The RetroArch combo of <i>Select</i> + <i>Start</i> = <i>Quit</i> now works on many SA-Emulators.</li>
                <li><i>Open Menu</i> is removed from <i>Select</i>.</li>
                <li><i>R5</i> = <i>A</i> button (this allows for great Wii controls on the right touchpad and pressing down the <i>R5</i> for A).</li>
                <li><i>L5</i> = <i>B</i> button.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Global hotkey changes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><i>Open Menu</i> is on <i>Y</i>.</li>
                <li><i>Increase Emulation Speed</i> is on <i>Dpad-UP</i>.</li>
                <li><i>Decrease Emulation Speed</i> is on <i>Dpad-Down</i>.</li>
                <li><i>Fullscreen OFF</i> command is removed (as emulators have migrated to toggle).</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Known issues:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The built-in auto-updater is not working (we are working on it). Discover is ok.</li>
                <li>Some emulators don't have hotkey support or have bugs affecting their hotkeys.</li>
            </ul>            
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.7.0b" date="2023-06-15">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.7.0b</url>
         <description>
            <p>New - System features:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>The Configurator has a new home inside the ES-DE main menu and thus the tools menu has been removed.</li>
               <li>The Configurator also has a .deskop icon for ease of access for both Steam Deck desktop mode and Linux Desktop users.</li>
               <li>Added RetroDECK auto updates on launch, this can be disabled from the Configurator this works in Game Mode for the Steam Deck.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>New RetroDECK Configurator features:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>The Configurator has a new structure, with more menus and options.</li>
               <li>The compression tool has been updated to allow for even more formats such as .zip in addition to the standard disc-based formats for certain systems.</li>
               <li>The compression tool has been updated to have an even stronger verification before a compression job starts.</li>
               <li>Added a global preset to swap A/B and X/Y in all supported emulators (aka N layout).</li>
               <li>Added a global preset to enable/disable Widescreen in all supported emulators, globally or per core/emulator.</li>
               <li>Added a global preset to enable/disable Ask-to-Exit prompts in all supported emulators.</li>
               <li>Added a preset to enable/disable Pegasus and NyNy77 Borders for RetroArch, globally or per core.</li>
               <li>Added an option to install Venomalia's Universial Dynamic Input Textures for Dolphin.</li>
               <li>Added an RetroDECK: About section</li>
               <li>Added an option to install the RetroDECK Steam Deck controller profile</li>
               <li>Added an “RetroDECK: Auto Updates” function that enables or disables auto updates on RetroDECK launch.</li>
               <li>Added a Semi-automated RPCS3 firmware installer.</li>
               <li>The Move Folder tool has been greatly expanded</li>
               <li>You can now move the entire folder or different folders as you choose. (WARNING! Please do not try to move the data to more exotic locations).</li>
               <li>The basic BIOS checker has been removed.</li>
               <li>The BIOS checker has been updated to look for over 120+ BIOS.</li>
               <li>RetroAchivements Login: Now logs into all supported emulators/cores at once.</li>
               <li>RetroAchivements Logout: Now logs out of all supported emulators/cores at once.</li>
               <li>Added RetroAchivements: Hardcore Mode, that lets you toggle hardcore mode for supported emulators/cores with a logged in RetroAchivements account.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Updates:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated ES-DE to the latest version.</li>
               <li>Updated RetroArch and the cores to latest versions.</li>
               <li>Updated all standalone emulators and to their latest versions.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Bugfixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Dolphin/Primehack Wii Mote controls have been redesigned for the Steam Deck to allow both for touch input or right radial as pointer and R2 emulates the Wii Remote Shake needed for certain games.</li>
               <li>Updated the RPCS3 to run better and with a better configuration. Read more on the wiki on how to install DLC and patches.</li>
               <li>RPCS3 and Duckstations save files where in the wrong directory. They have been moved to fit the overall inside the RetroDECK Framework. If you have any issues, contact us on discord or add them on github.</li>
               <li>We made a unique PICO-8 wrapper that makes it runs better in a flatpak environment.</li>
               <li>Fixed an avcodec issue that caused some roms for certain emulators to break.</li>
               <li>Changed the ES-DE progress bar color</li>
               <li>Changed how Yuzu builds are handled and should allow for better Yuzu updates.</li>
               <li>Added a low space warning on launch.</li>
               <li>Various backend improvements and fixes.</li>
               <li>Added the foss Capsimg BIOS for the Amiga RetroArch core.</li>
               <li>Implemented ES-DE's experimental theme downloader. For fresh new installs we only now ship one theme: ArtBookNext (as all other themes can be downloaded from the interface).</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.6b" date="2023-04-26">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.6b</url>
         <description>
            <p>Bug fixes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed ES-DE that was showing the update notification</li>
               <li>PSX: Swanstation is back as default emulator</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.5b" date="2023-04-07">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.5b</url>
         <description>
            <p>Bug fixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Rolled back to latest working Yuzu</li>
               <li>Improved Yuzu performance by tweaking GPU options</li>
               <li>Fixed an issue where the default theme was not loaded</li>
               <li>Removed unavailable emulators entries</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.4b" date="2023-04-04">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.4b</url>
         <description>
            <p>New features - General:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated to ES-DE 2.0</li>
               <li>Added the NSO Menu Interpreted theme</li>
               <li>Updated all included themes</li>
               <li>Updated the Emulators/RetroArch + cores</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Bug fixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed an audio issue in the Primehack configuration</li>
               <li>Various backend fixes</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.3b" date="2023-03-24">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.3b</url>
         <description>
            <p>New features - General:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Added support for multiple file compression via CLI.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>RetroDECK Configurator:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Added support for multiple file compression in the Configurator.</li>
               <li>Added safety y/n prompts to the reset functions.</li>
               <li>Fixed some missing layout changes.</li>
               <li>Renamed "Reset All" to "Reset RetroDECK".</li>
               <li>Moved configurator into the RO partition for futher enhancements.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Bug fixes and other changes:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed a bug in the compression tool with certain filenames with spaces.</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where some folders were recursively symlinked.</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where some emulator configs were not correctly deployed.</li>
               <li>Fixed the Configurator BIOS tool looking in the wrong location (Thanks sofauxboho for the report!).</li>
               <li>Fixed a manifest bug that caused a conflict between Dolphin and Primehack in certain scenarios.</li>
               <li>Implemented new configurations for Yuzu and Citra thanks to the big config file changes in the latest emulator updates in both emulators.</li>
               <li>Removed leftover files from Legacy PCSX2.</li>
               <li>Removed the legacy "Reset Tools" command from Configurator and CLI.</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.2b" date="2023-03-15">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.2b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Persistent configurations when updating RetroDECK, this means your custom configurations should be saved across future versions. (We also laid groundwork for dynamic persistent configurations, more on that in a future update. This is the reason why it has taken quite long to fix this).</li>
               <li>Added Primehack controller profiles for both Xbox and Nintendo button layouts</li>
               <li>Added a warning when running RetroDECK in desktop mode, as not all controls will work properly.</li>
               <li>Added CLI for CHD compression (chdman) of single games</li>
               <li>Reworked CLI commands and added safety y/n confirmations for the reset arguments.</li>
               <li>New structure for more easy access to various tools</li>
               <li>The power user prompt only needs to be answered once</li>
               <li>Added tool to do CHD compression (chdman) of single games (multi-game batch compression coming in a future update)</li>
               <li>Added tool to check for common BIOS files</li>
               <li>Added tool to check for common multi-file game structure issues</li>
               <li>Fixed Primehack initial configuration as it was broken (will automatically reset the emulator just this once)</li>
               <li>Fixed Duckstation initial configuration as it was broken (will require user-performed reset just this once)</li>
               <li>Fixed Pico-8 initial configuration as it was broken.</li>
               <li>Fixed Pico-8 dual bios folders. The program files pico8_dyn,pico8.dat and pico8 have to be manually moved to the correct location~/retrodeck/bios/pico-8/. The old ~/retrodeck/bios/pico8/ is renamed ~/retrodeck/bios/pico8_olddata/ to avoid confusion on where to put files. After the files have moved the pico8_olddata folder can be deleted.</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug that made the Dolphin RetroArch core not working properly (the standalone version of Dolphin always worked and is the default)</li>
               <li>Various backend fixes</li>
               <li>Updated all Emulators, RetroArch and libreretro cores. (PLEASE NOTE! ES-DE was not updated to version 2.0, this will be done in the next version of RetroDECK as we need more time to work on the new theme format).</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.1b" date="2023-02-21">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.1b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated all the emulators and cores at their latest versions (except for Duckstation)</li>
               <li>Removed Ryjuinx as it was broken (sorry)</li>
               <li>Removed deprecated emulators from Configurator (eg. Legacy PCSX2)</li>
               <li>Added CLI option to run Configurator directly</li>
               <li>Added "--configure" option to RetroDECK CLI</li>
               <li>Adjusted Configurator window sizes</li>
               <li>Made file-moving code safer</li>
               <li>Fixed Primehack preconfiguration and Configurator entry</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where the hidden files were not moved during the directory preparation</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where the symlinks were recursively placed inside the prepeared paths</li>
               <li>Fixed issue with missing symlink after RetroDECK base directory was moved somewhere else&gt;</li>
               <li>Fixed Duckstation preconfiguration</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.6.0b" date="2022-12-24">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.6.0b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Added Ryujinx</li>
               <li>Added Primehack</li>
               <li>Merged all tools into single Configurator</li>
               <li>The Configurator can now move the whole retrodeck folder eslewhere (not just the ROMs one)</li>
               <li>The Configurator can now reset a single emulator, all RetroArch or all Standaloned configs (so there is no need to di it via CLI anymore</li>
               <li>The first install is now asking where to place the whole retrodeck folder instead of requesting the location of the ROMs folder only.</li>
               <li>Fix: PCSX2-QT is now looking for saves in the correct directory ~/retrodeck/saves/ps2/memcards and not in ~/retrodeck/saves/ps2/pcsx2/memcards</li>
               <li>Introduced a fix if/when SteamOS will change the SDCard default location.</li>
               <li>Updated RetroArch to v1.14.0</li>
               <li>Updated PPSSPP (SA) to v1.13.2</li>
               <li>Updated Citra (SA) to nightly-1802</li>
               <li>Updated PCSX2-QT to nightly v1.7.3501</li>
               <li>Updated Dolphin (SA) to latest on 31/10/2022</li>
               <li>Updated Xemu to v0.7.71</li>
               <li>Updated RPCS3 to latest on 31/10/2022</li>
               <li>Updated Duckstation to latest on 31/10/2022</li>
               <li>Migrated Yuzu from appimage mainline-1271 and reconfigured</li>
               <li>Removed old PCSX2 (non-qt)</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.5.3b" date="2022-10-26">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.5.3b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed inaccessible RetroArch shaders folder</li>
               <li>Fixed PSP saving issue when using RetroArch core</li>
               <li>Fixed ROM visibility for Dolphin when running standalone, which should address ability to use AR/Gecko codes</li>
               <li>Changed default RPCS3 launch method to fix games not starting properly</li>
               <li>Fixed PCSX2-QT autosave loading issue</li>
               <li>Fixed RetroAchievements login on PCSX2-QT</li>
               <li>Added Citra SA sysdata folder to RetroDECK BIOS folder</li>
               <li>Added Yuzu save folders to RetroDECK saves folder</li>
               <li>Made Citra standalone the default 3DS emulator</li>
               <li>Progress window during emulator initialization where it can look like RetroDECK has crashed</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.5.2b" date="2022-10-13">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.5.2b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>VERY IMPORTANT: We are moving your saves! This can take time on the first boot. If you miss some saves they are not gone. Please read more in the wiki.</li>
               <li>Fixed Citra save migration folder</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where the videos were not played correctly in some cases</li>
               <li>Fixed the Rewind tool</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.5.1b" date="2022-10-12">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.5.1b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>VERY IMPORTANT: We are moving your saves! This can take time on the first boot. If you miss some saves they are not gone. Please read more in the wiki.</li>
               <li>Fixed a bug where Yuzu was not compiled correctly</li>
               <li>Updated Yuzu</li>
               <li>New Logo and Theme</li>
               <li>Two new themes added: Alekfull-NX-Light and Retrofix-Revisited</li>
               <li>Updated ES-DE to 1.2.6</li>
               <li>Implemented the first steps towards a universal Emulator Configuration Tool in the TOOLS menu</li>
               <li>Ability to log into your RetroAchievements account under the TOOLS menu for RetroArch only (supported standalones coming soon)</li>
               <li>Updated RetroArch and all the standalone emulators</li>
               <li>Added several free assets/fonts for RetroArch, PPSSPP, XEMU and BlueMSX</li>
               <li>Added a new DEFAULT Emulator for the PS2: PCSX2-QT (the former PCSX2 default emulator is now called "PCSX2 (Legacy)")</li>
               <li>Changed the DEFAULT Emulator for the PSX: Swanstation (Libretro) Core</li>
               <li>Added a new Standalone Emulator for the PSX: Duckstation</li>
               <li>Enhanced XEMU (XBOX) experience</li>
               <li>And more, for the complete patch notes please check the wiki...</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.5.0b" date="2022-10-11">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.5.0b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>VERY IMPORTANT: We are moving your saves! This can take time on the first boot. If you miss some saves they are not gone. Please read more in the wiki.</li>
               <li>New Logo and Theme</li>
               <li>Two new themes added: Alekfull-NX-Light and Retrofix-Revisited</li>
               <li>Updated ES-DE to 1.2.6</li>
               <li>Implemented the first steps towards a universal Emulator Configuration Tool in the TOOLS menu</li>
               <li>Ability to log into your RetroAchievements account under the TOOLS menu for RetroArch only (supported standalones coming soon)</li>
               <li>Updated RetroArch and all the standalone emulators</li>
               <li>Added several free assets/fonts for RetroArch, PPSSPP, XEMU and BlueMSX</li>
               <li>Added a new DEFAULT Emulator for the PS2: PCSX2-QT (the former PCSX2 default emulator is now called "PCSX2 (Legacy)")</li>
               <li>Changed the DEFAULT Emulator for the PSX: Swanstation (Libretro) Core</li>
               <li>Added a new Standalone Emulator for the PSX: Duckstation</li>
               <li>Enhanced XEMU (XBOX) experience</li>
               <li>And more, for the complete patch notes please check the wiki...</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.5b" date="2022-07-20">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.5b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed a bug where new symlinks were not created correctly and users couldn't scrape their games</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Known Issues:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>PCSX2: due to its limitation, the standalone PCSX2 doesn't have any way to set the hotkeys, so no save and load state, no quit button. In order to quit press: STEAM -&gt; PCSX2 -&gt; (X) CLOSE WINDOW, be aware that the state is not automatically saved</li>
               <li>Due to a Steam limitation, external controllers and keyboard seems not to be working, expecially in the desktop mode</li>
            </ul>
            IMPORTANT NOTE:
        At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version they may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.4b" date="2022-07-18">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.4b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Yuzu: Disabled shader caching as it was broken</li>
               <li>Yuzu: Switched from vulkan to opengl as vulkan is experimental and it's not working correctly for the games majority, you can set vulkan by opening tuzu from Tools -&gt; Start Yuzu</li>
               <li>Yuzu: Edited Hotkeys (see wiki)</li>
               <li>Yuzu: Increased performances</li>
               <li>Yuzu: Fixed graphics and scaling</li>
               <li>Yuzu: Fixed right control stick</li>
               <li>PCSX2: Symlinked bios/pcsx folder in /bios to solve issue#63</li>
               <li>Backend: Uploaded a test Steam Controller config, you can download it from community controller configs on Steam</li>
               <li>Backend: Unhidden .themes and .downloaded_media folders</li>
               <li>Backend: Moved the lockfile in the internal folders</li>
               <li>Backend: General code cleanup.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Known Issues:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>PCSX2: due to its limitation, the standalone PCSX2 doesn't have any way to set the hotkeys, so no save and load state, no quit button. In order to quit press: STEAM -&gt; PCSX2 -&gt; (X) CLOSE WINDOW, be aware that the state is not automatically saved</li>
               <li>Due to a Steam limitation, external controllers and keyboard seems not to be working, expecially in the desktop mode</li>
            </ul>
            IMPORTANT NOTE:
        At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version they may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.3b" date="2022-07-07">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.3b</url>
         <description>
            <p>
               <b>Emulators:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated all the emulators at the latest available version.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Backend:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Manifest code cleanup.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Known Issues:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>PCSX2: due to its limitation, the standalone PCSX2 doesn't have any way to set the hotkeys, so no save and load state, no quit button. In order to quit press: STEAM -&gt; PCSX2 -&gt; (X) CLOSE WINDOW, be aware that the state is not automatically saved</li>
               <li>Due to a Steam limitation, external controllers and keyboard seems not to be working, expecially in the desktop mode</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>IMPORTANT NOTE:</b>
               At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version they may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.
            </p>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.2b" date="2022-07-01">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.2b</url>
         <description>
            <p>
               <b>Emulators:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated all the emulators at the latest available version.</li>
               <li>DOLPHIN (SA): Fixed a bug where Dolphin couldn't be properly configured. If it's still misconfigured please run `flatpak run net.retrodeck.retrodeck --reset-sa` in order to reset all the standalone emulators, including Dolphin.</li>
               <li>CITRA (SA): Reconfigured controls and hotkeys.</li>
               <li>MELONDS (SA): Reconfigured controls.</li>
               <li>GAMBATTE (LIBRETRO): Added GB colorization.</li>
               <li>RETROARCH (LIBRETRO): Tweaked some configs and fixed some overlapping hotkeys (FPS was same as Show Menu action).</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Backend:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Removed some broken tools that will be reintroduced once fixed, including the roms moving tool.</li>
               <li>Updated ES-DE configs (es_find_rules, es_settings, es_systems).</li>
               <li>Manifest trimmend and general code cleanup.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Known Issues:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>PCSX2: due to its limitation, the standalone PCSX2 doesn't have any way to set the hotkeys, so no save and load state, no quit button. In order to quit press: STEAM -&gt; PCSX2 -&gt; (X) CLOSE WINDOW, be aware that the state is not automatically saved</li>
               <li>Due to a Steam limitation, external controllers and keyboard seems not to be working, expecially in the desktop mode</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>IMPORTANT NOTE:</b>
               At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version they may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.
            </p>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.1b" date="2022-05-11">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.1b</url>
         <description>
            <p>
               <b>Emulators:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Tweaked various emulator configs</li>
               <li>The emulators that was showing a small viewport like N64, Wii, GC, and Dreamcast are now showing a more appropriate viewport</li>
               <li>Fixed home path in MelonDS (SA)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Frontend:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated ES-DE to 1.2.4</li>
               <li>RetroDECK doesn't open ES-DE anymore during the first setup, almost everything is now automated: HURRAY!</li>
               <li>Now a custom roms path can be selected if SD Card is selected and the SD Card is not found in the default path</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Backend:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed a bug where the folders where not symlinked correclty</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>Known Issues:</b>
            </p>
            <ul>
               <li>PCSX2: due to its limitation, the standalone PCSX2 doesn't have any way to set the hotkeys, so no save and load state, no quit button. In order to quit press: STEAM -&gt; PCSX2 -&gt; (X) CLOSE WINDOW, be aware that the state is not automatically saved</li>
               <li>External controllers and keyboard seems not to be working, expecially in the desktop mode</li>
               <li>Yuzu makes RetroDECK freeze in some situations, like if the rom is a bad dump</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
               <b>IMPORTANT NOTE:</b>
               At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version they may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.
            </p>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.4.0b" date="2022-05-26">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.4.0b</url>
         <description>
            <p>Emulators:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Yuzu was broken: fixed</li>
               <li>Dolphin-libretro is now the default emulator as Dolphin (Standalone) seems to be broken</li>
            </ul>
            <p>New Standalone emulators:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>RPCS3</li>
               <li>PPSSPP</li>
               <li>CITRA</li>
               <li>MelonDS</li>
               <li>PICO-8</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Tools:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Added tools to start each standalone emulator</li>
               <li>Added a tool to start PICO-8's SPLORE</li>
               <li>Fixed the Move ROMs tool (probably)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Frontend:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Updated ES-DE to 1.2.4 and redirected to the new repo</li>
               <li>Updated Art-Book theme to fix the mising images for n3ds and pico-8</li>
               <li>Now The quit button is showing "Quit RetroDECK"</li>
               <li>Added RetroDECK version in the ES-DE main menu</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Backend:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Wrapper complete rewrite, now it's faster, tidier, solid</li>
               <li>Wrapper: user data is now backup and moved when managing the internal folders</li>
               <li>Introduced versioning: now the version is visible by CLI or in the options menu</li>
               <li>Rewrote cooker.yml workflow as the old one was no more useful for the scope</li>
               <li>Removed the bios/bios folder that in some situations is mistakenly created</li>
               <li>Logs are now into ~/retrodeck/.logs however they must be improved</li>
               <li>Moved the scraped data folder into ~/retrodeck/.downloaded_data for backup purposes and to avoid data loss when resetting RetroDECK</li>
               <li>Moved themes folder in ~/retrodeck/.downloaded_data, same as above</li>
               <li>Updated es_find_rules.xml</li>
               <li>Updated es_systems.xml: some default emulators are changed, if you cannot load the game is maybe because of that, you can still choose the former emulator from the list</li>
               <li>Added post-install scripts, now deleting ~/retrodeck/.log or ~/.var/app/net.retrodeck.retrodeck is no more needed (hopefully)</li>
               <li>Added CLI arguments, run flatpak run net.retrodeck.retrodeck -h for more info</li>
               <li>Added a CLI option to reset RetroDECK --reset</li>
               <li>Replaced Kdialog with Zenity</li>
               <li>Added manifest: this should fix the Discover bug</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Known Issues:</p>
            <ul>
               <li>Controller is not configured for most of the standalone emulators, I will configure them when I will get my Steam Deck (ETA mid June)</li>
               <li>External controllers seems not to be working</li>
               <li>Yuzu makes RetroDECK freeze in some situations, like if the rom is a bad dump</li>
            </ul>
            <p>IMPORTANT NOTE:
          At the moment the emulator configs are reset during every update, this was made because every version may bring new configurations, please back them up if you did some manual configs.</p>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.3.1b" date="2022-04-26">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.3.1b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Fixed Dolphin: now Dolphin (Standalone) is the default emulator for GC/Wii.</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.3.0b" date="2022-04-26">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.3.0b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Migrated everything from the old domain com.xargon.retrodeck to net.retrodeck.retrodeck to be aligned with flathub standards</li>
               <li>Fixed and enhanced all the tools</li>
               <li>Added 'Start Yuzu' tool</li>
               <li>Swapped a/b buttons on RetroArch</li>
               <li>Tweaked some RetroArch configs</li>
               <li>Fixed RetroArch Hotkeys</li>
               <li>Added standalone PCSX2</li>
               <li>Added standalone XEMU</li>
               <li>Added standalone DOLPHIN</li>
               <li>Reconfigured standalone YUZU</li>
               <li>Updated EmulationStation Desktop Edition</li>
               <li>Updated the default Art Book DE theme</li>
               <li>Updated various backend scripts</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.2.0b" date="2022-04-17">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.2.0b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Migrated everything from the old building script to a full fledged yaml in order to being published on Discover</li>
               <li>Fixed SD Card issues</li>
               <li>Improved installer script</li>
               <li>Tweaked RetroArch configs</li>
               <li>Added tool for relocating ROMs location from/to internal to/from external</li>
               <li>Added PCSX2 and Yuzu emulators (but not yet integrated in ES-DE)</li>
               <li>Created cooker channel, more info in Discord and on RetroDECK-cooker on GitHub</li>
               <li>Cooker will auto build when a change is pushed/PRed</li>
               <li>Same as above with main</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.1.1b" date="2022-04-03">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.1.1b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Removed some debug stuff (press any key to continue)</li>
               <li>Fixed ROMs folder</li>
               <li>Fixed SD Card logic</li>
               <li>Desktop file improved</li>
               <li>Improved installer messages</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
      <release version="0.1.0b" date="2022-04-03">
         <url>https://github.com/XargonWan/RetroDECK/releases/tag/0.1.0b</url>
         <description>
            <ul>
               <li>Pick up and play, just put your roms and bios in /retrodeck/roms and /retrodeck/bios folders.</li>
               <li>SD Card support</li>
               <li>Fancy interface provided by ES-DE and Art-Book-Next-DE</li>
               <li>All retro systems available until PS2</li>
               <li>Auto load/save states</li>
               <li>Scraping</li>
               <li>RetroAchievements (must be manually set)</li>
            </ul>
         </description>
      </release>
   </releases>
</component>